Guide to the George F. Kunz Papers 1862-1932 MS 358
New-York Historical Society
George F. Kunz papers
1862, 1880-1932
New-York Historical Society
Kunz, George Frederick, 1856-1932
MS 358
2.5 Linear feet in six document boxes
The collection includes about 2400 letters to gemologist and mineralogist George Frederick Kunz (1856-1932), with some carbon copies of his outgoing letters and some ephemera related to his activities. The letters are from hundreds of correspondents, and date mostly from the early 1900s and into the 1920s, though there are many from earlier and later years. The subject matter ranges across Kunz's professional and personal interests, including correspondence with publishers and editors; academics and others seeking or providing information about gems and precious stones; members and fellow officers of the many committees and clubs he participated in, concerning organizational activities; and individuals and organizations seeking his financial or other support.
Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically by correspondent, meaning the individual signing the letter, not, in the case of organizations, the name on the letterhead. It is unlikely that the arrangement precisely reflects Kunz's original order. At the close of the collection are a few dinner menus, receipts, and other printed formats.
Biographical / Historical
George Frederick Kunz (1856-1932) was a renowned mineralogist and gemologist. He was born in New York City and raised in Hoboken, New Jersey. He attended public schools and Cooper Union, but did not earn a degree there. Rather, he was largely self-taught, and developed an expertise that led to honorary degrees from Columbia University, University of Marburg and Knox University. He also earned international recognition, including the Legion of Honor of France and an officer of the Rising Sun of Japan. At the age of 23, in 1879, he joined Tiffany & Company as a gem expert; he remained with the firm for the rest of his life.
Kunz was enormously productive. He was in charge of the mining exhibits at the Paris Exposition (1889), the Kimberley, South Africa, Exposition (1892), and the Chicago Columbian Exposition (1893) and was a special agent at the Paris Exposition (1900) and commissioner on radium at the St. Louis Exposition (1904). A gem collector and discoverer, he traveled the world in search of pearls and gemstones, which he sometimes named after his associates and patrons, calling one rare find tiffanyite, after Charles L. Tiffany, and another morganite, after J. Pierpont Morgan. Kunzite, a mineral, is named after him. He wrote prodigiously; a bibliography maintained by the Gemological Institute of America is 23 pages long. Among his books was Natal Stones, Sentiments, and Superstitions connected with Precious Stones, which was printed each year and given as gifts to customers of Tiffany & Co.
Kunz was active in a large number of social, literary, cultural, and religious organizations. Among these were the American Numismatic and Archeological Society (later the American Numismatic Society), Authors Club, Grolier Club, Century Association (also known as the Century Club), Union League Club, City History Club of New York, Church Club of New York, the Layman's Club of the Cathedral of St. John the Divine, American Scenic and Historic Society for Preservation, and the New-York Historical Society. He was a founder of the Sulgrave Institution and the Museums of the Peaceful Arts in New York.
Beyond his ongoing professional and organizational work, Kunz was also active in a variety of single purpose initiatives, including the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission (1909), serving with Cornelius Vanderbilt on the Mayor's Committee for the Entertainment of the U.S. Atlantic Fleet (1915), president of the Joan of Arc Statue Committee (Riverside Park, 1915), and the Central Park Shakespeare Garden Committee (1915).
Kunz married Sophia Hanforth in 1879. They had two children. Sophia died in 1912. Kunz later married Opal Logan Giberson (1896?-1967); the marriage was annulled in 1929, though the couple continued to live together. Kunz maintained a country home in Mohegan Lake, Westchester County, New York, where he was Senior Warden of St. Mary's Church. He died of a cerebral hemorrhage in June 1932.
(This note was derived from various on-line sources, including Paul F. Kerr's memorial in "The American Mineralogist" of March 1933, a biographical note on the American Numismatic Society's website, Wikipedia, and others, as well as documents in the collection.)
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was compiled from two sources: About 2100 items were purchased on November 21, 1939, at Parke-Bernet Galleries Sale 134 (lot 28). A donation of about 300 additional documents was received in August 1975 from E.L. Sampter.
Scope and Contents
The collection primarily includes over 2400 letters to George Frederick Kunz. The letters range across hundreds of correspondents, many of whom are represented by only one item. There are many letters from the 1880s-1890s, but most date from the early 1900s and into the 1920s, with a few from the last years of Kunz's life. The collection also holds some carbon copies of Kunz's outgoing letters. Kunz's intended replies or other disposition are noted in his hand on some of the letters; many of the letters also have shorthand notation on them, whether by Kunz or, perhaps more likely, a Tiffany secretary.
The subject matter ranges across Kunz's professional and personal interests. A sizable amount is fairly mundane, and includes acknowledgements of books received from Kunz, acceptances/regrets of invitations, courtesies, pleasantries, and letters of introduction or requests for them. Correspondence with publishers and editors comprise much of the correspondence, and this includes acceptances or rejections of proposed articles, editorial arrangements for publications, and the like. Requests of Kunz for information about gems and precious stones or providing him requested information is common. One of the most interesting documents in this regard was from the Burmese archaeologist Taw Sein Ko, who provided his paper on Burmese necromancy, with hand-drawn figures.
Much of the collection documents Kunz's involvement with an array of organizations. Letters request his financial support (including one from Helen Keller for the American Foundation for the Blind); for nomination to the Grolier, Century, or other club Kunz was affiliated with; and for invitations to events. More personal appeals to Kunz as mentor and patron are also documented here. These include women such as Laura Ivins, who in 1908 describes her work as a newspaper reporter in seeking Kunz's help in finding a position in the field in New York; and Isabelle Stone, who describes her struggles in 1906 to advance as a professor of physics. Along these lines, there is exceptional, extensive correspondence ranging from 1896 to 1924 with writer and editor Gardner C. Teall (1876-1956). In his letters, Teall describes his financial, health, and career struggles and his employment in various publishing houses (with Phelps Publishing, Robert Grier Cooke, House & Garden, and American Homes & Garden, among others); Kunz provides financial support, encouragement, job leads, and recommendations over the years.
The container list below provides a list of almost all correspondents in the collection. (Some are illegible or a few could not be fully discerned and so are in alphabetical "miscellaneous" folders.) To the extent that an individual correspondent was perceived by the processing archivist to be writing on behalf of an organization or was affiliated with an organization in some meaningful way in relation to the letter's content, an attempt was made during processing to identify that and include the organization's name in the container list as well. It is likely, however, that many such organizational references, particularly for routine invitations and the like, are not recorded in the container list.
Related Materials
N-YHS holds three additional George Kunz letters in its American Historical Manuscripts Collection. Call phrase for these letters is AHMC - Kunz, George F.
N-YHS also holds several books, pamphlets and other print matter authored by or related to Kunz. These can be found by searching on "Kunz" in Bobcat.
Beyond N-YHS, Kunz-related papers can be found at various institutions. A concise summary of several of these can be found at the blog "The Contributions of Frederick Kunz" though a Worldcat search will be more comprehensive.
Associations, institutions, etc. -- Membership -- New York (State) -- New York.; Authors and publishers -- United States.; Gems -- Research.; Gemologists.; Learned institutions and societies.; Memorialization.; Philanthropy.; Letters (correspondence).; Teall, Gardner C.; Authors Club (New York, N.Y.); Century Association (New York, N.Y.); Grolier Club; Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission
- Abbe, Catherine A.B., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abbott, James, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adams, Edward D., 1901, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adams, Francis M. (St. Mary's Rectory, Lake Mohegan, NY), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adams, Thomas (Regional Plan of New York and Its Environs), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adamson, Robert (National American Bank), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adler, Elmer, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agar, John, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alden, Henry Mills (Harper & Brothers), 1890-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aldrich, H.L. (Scientific American), 1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexander [first name is unclear. Possibly two different correspondents] (Century Association), 1916, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexander, Charles B. (New York State Department of Education), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexander, Mary H., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allen, A.W. (Engineering and Mining Journal), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allen, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allen, William H., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Director of the Institute for Public Service requests Kunz's support for the attached "Proposal submitted to the City News Association for cooperative governmental research and news service by the leading newspapers of Greater New York."
- Alliot, Hector (Grolier Club), 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ames, Louis Annin (Sons of the American Revolution, Empire State Society), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  On committee together to conserve Thomas Jefferson's birthplace.
- Anderson, Eunice G. (State of Wyoming, Historical Department), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Appleton, Charles H., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arctowka, Jane, 1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Armbuster, Anna, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Armstrong, Frank C. (Rev.), 1926, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Armstrong provides names of members of the committee to erect a World War I shrine in the nature of a chapel in St. Paul's Church, Hoboken, NJ.
- Armstrong, Mary Stuart, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arsdedt, Countess d', undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arzruni, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Atkins, A.B. (Encyclopedia Britannica), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Austin, Henry, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Avery, Samuel P., 1893-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bache, Rene, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Backus, Emma S., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bacon, George A. ("The Academy" Journal of Secondary Education), 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Badel, Emile, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Joseph Baer & Co., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bain, George G., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bancroft, Margaret, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barker, George F. (American Philosophical Society), 1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barlow, Samuel L.M., 1885, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barnouw, A.J. (Columbia U., Department of Germanic Languages), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barrett, John, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barrett, Laura Day, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barrus, C., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bartlett, E.E. (Gutenberg Memorial Committee), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bartlett, Henrietta C., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Baskerville, Charles, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bass, Mrs. James Madison (National Shakespeare Federation/Shakespeare Club of New York), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Batchelder (editor), 1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bates, Albert C., 1917, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bates, L., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Battle, George Gordon, 1913, 1915, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Church Club; Civic Forum; Mayor's Independence Day Committee
- Baward, George Grey, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Baxley, William H. (Westchester County Committee, Young Men's Christian Association), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beale, William G., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beard, Daniel Carter (Boys Life magazine), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beatty, W. Gedney, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beekman, W.S., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beer, William (Howard Memorial Library), 1907, 1915, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Belknap, Waldron P. (Bankers Trust), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bell, A. (Rev.) (West Pennsylvania Synod), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bellis, Berton (Classic Press), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Benedict, Harry E., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Benedict, Henry Harper, 1921-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Benjamin, Marcus (Appleton's Cyclopedia), 1887 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Benjamin, William Evarts, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bennitt, Mark (Universal Exposition Publishing Co), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bentley, Walter E. (Rev.) (Actors' Church Alliance of America), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Benton, Edmund S., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berg, Charles I., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berk, Carl, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berkey, Charles P. (Columbia U., Department of Geology and Mineralogy), 1913-1914, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bertram, James, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bickerton, Spencer, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bickmore, Albert S. (American Museum of Natural History), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Biddle, A.J. Drexel (Drexel Biddle Bible Classes of the Middle Atlantic States), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bigelow, Francis H., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bigelow, F.S. (Saturday Evening Post), 1906-1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bigelow, John, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bigelow, Poultney, 1920-1930, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Biggers, V.W. (Associated Press), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Biggers, of the Associated Press, presents himself as a candidate for the director of publicity for Kunz's Museum of Peaceful Arts.
- Bingham, Hiram (Yale U,; Harvard U.), 1902-1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Correspondence relating to books and expeditions to South/Central America and Mexico.
- Bingham, Theodore A., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bishop, Caroline, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bispham, William (Grolier Club), 1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Blake, W.B. ("The Independent"), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Blake, W.W., 1899, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1917, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bliss, Cornelius Newton, Jr., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bliss, Dwight, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bliss, Robert, 1907, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bocock, John Paul, 1901, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Some of Bocock's letters refer to attempts to place a pistol collection at the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
- Bok, Edward W. (Ladies' Home Journal), 1912, 1917-1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Boldt, G. (Waldorf Astoria Hotel Co), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bolton, Charles Knowles (Boston Athenaeum), 1902 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bolton, H. Carrington (Trinity College, Conn), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bordon, Bertram H., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bostwick, C.D. (Cornell U), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boswell, Helen Varick, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Invitation to Mrs. Kunz (Opal Kunz), aviatrix and head of the Ninety-nine Club, to be a guest speaker at The Woman's Forum on the topic of women in aviation and her new organization.
- Bowdoin, W. (The Independent), 1903-1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bowen, Clarence W. (New York Genealogical and Biographical Society), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bower, Claude G., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bowman, Isaiah (American Geographical Society), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boykin, J.C. (U.S. Department of the Interior), 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brauman, John W. (Century Association), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Braun, W.A. (Columbia U., Roosevelt Memorial Exhibition), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brennecke, Ernest (The World), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brett, Everett & Margaret, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  A letter of thanks from Everett and a poem "The Flag" by Margaret.
- Bridge, Jr., H.P. (Keystone Publishing Co), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brigham, A.F., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brinton, Daniel H., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brisbane, Arthur (New York Evening Journal), 1907, 1917-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brisbane, Phoebe Cary, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bristol, George P. (Cornell U), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Britt, Albert (Knox College), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Britton, Elizabeth (Columbia College, Torrey Botanical Club), 1886 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Britton, N.L. (Columbia College, Department of Botany), 1895, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bromley, Allan R. (Columbia College, Library), 1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brooks, Emerson (Boy Rangers of America), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brooks, John Graham (National Consumers' League), 1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brown, Elmer Ellsworth (New York University), 1915-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Invitations to annual dinner of the Council of New York University
- Brown, Francis (Union Theological Seminary), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brown, Henry Collins (Museum of the City of New York), 1921-1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brown, W.T. Watkins, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bruno, Guido (Bruno's Weekly), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bucher, John Calvin (Peekskill Military Academy), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Buck, J.H. (Gorham Manufacturing Co), 1902 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Budge, E.A. Wallis (British Museum), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Buel, C.C. (Century magazine), 1891, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Buhler, M.E., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bullen, Henry Lewis (Typographic Library and Museum), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bumpus, H.C. (Tufts College; American Museum of Natural History), 1908-1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Burleigh, George W. (Church Club of New York), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Burlingame, Gayle, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Burrage, Albert C., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bush, Irving T. (Bush Terminal Co), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Butler, Nicholas Murray (Columbia U), 1906-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Misc. B., 1890, 1894, 1901,1931, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes, among others, a letter from the Director-General of the Pan-American Exposition 1901.
- Cadman, S. Parkes (Rev.) (Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Caldwell, Edward, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carlton, Henry Guy, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carnegie, Margaret, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carryl, Charles (Grolier Club), 1888 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  On Grolier Club stationery, informs Kunz that he has been appointed as chairman of a subcommittee to organize the exhibition of Americana.
- Carus, Paul ("The Monist" and "The Open Court"), 1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Carus comments on his experience with his compositors in relation to the 8 hour workday.
- Cary, Edward (New York Times), 1902 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cassot, Arthur (Manhattan Press Clipping Bureau), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cattell, J. McKeen (Science magazine), 1912-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cattell, Ware (Scientific Monthly), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cauldwell, William (Successful American magazine), 1902 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cesnola, Luigi Palma di, 1899-1902 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chamberlin, Rollin T. (University of Chicago), 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chandler, J.A.C. (College of William & Mary), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chapple, Joe Mitchell (National Magazine), 1915-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chase, Charles F. (National Conference of Church Clubs), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chase, John Carroll, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chester, Georgiana W., 1903, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chichester, Chas. F. (Century Co), 1892-1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Childs, William Hamlin, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chisholm, Hugh (Encyclopedia Britannica), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chittenden, L.E., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Church, A.H., 1891, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Church, Jr., John A., undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clark, Lotta A. (American Pageant Association), 1913, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clark, Mary O., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clark, William A., 1913, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clark, William Bullock (Johns Hopkins U, Geological Lab), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clarke, John M. (New York State Museum), 1901-1904 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clarke, Lewis L. (Mayor's Committee on National Defense and Preparedness), 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clearwater, Alphonso T., 1899-1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Among other subjects, Clearwater, who is president of the Commissioners of the State Reservation at Niagara, sends passes to the reservation's features (1924).
- Cleveland, Mary B., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Clifford, William (Metropolitan Museum of Art, Library), 1904 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Clos, Jean Henry (Yorktown Historical Society), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cochran, Jr., Thomas (Astor Trust Co), 1909, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cole, Alfred Bartlett, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Colles, Julia Keese, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Collins, Laura Sedgwick, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Among other documents, includes the sheet music for Collins's "Hail! Gentle Peace" (1909), written for the Young People's League for International Federation, and "The New Patriotism" (1916), from Marion Mills Miller's pageant "The Declaration of Independence."
- Colloque, E.W. (Rev.), 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Comparetti, T.L., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Compton, George Brokaw (Hughes National College League), 1910, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Condon, Nellie Louise, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Conrad, (Rev. Fr.) ("Veronica's Veil" Executive Committee), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cooke, Helen Temple, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Holds a letter and written statement about Cooke from Mabel (Jenkins?) to Opal Kunz concerning the possibility of George Kunz asking the Japanese ambassador to honor Cooke in some way; a copy of the resulting typed request from Kunz to the Japanese Consul-General is also enclosed.
- Cooke, Robert Grier (publishers), 1907, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Coolidge, William D. (General Electric Co), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Coomaraswamy, A., 1903 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Coon, Spencer H., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Copeland, Melvin T. (Harvard U., Bureau of Business Research), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Copsey, Vivian, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Corcoran, W.W., 1880 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Corning, Edward, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cox, Charles F., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Coyney, Weston (N.Y. Recorder), 1894 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cozzens, Horatio G., 1907-1916 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Craigie, Mary E. (National Shakespeare Federation), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crary, R. Fulton Jr., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cravath, Paul D., 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crocker, Stuart (General Electric Co), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crocker, William H., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crofut, Hobart L.S., 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crompton, William, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cromwell, William Nelson, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cromwell, John Franklin, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crowningshield, Frank (Conde Nast), 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cuddihy, R.J. (Funk & Wagnalls), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cuntz, John H., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Currey, J.B. (Metropolitan Savings Bank), 1903 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Curtis, Cyrus H.K. (Public Ledger Co), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Curtis, William E. (Chicago Record), 1894 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cutting, W. Bayard (Mrs.), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Misc. C, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Daggett, Windsor P., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)